<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>ACM on Tomial's Blog</title><link>https://tomial.github.io/tags/acm/</link><description>Recent content in ACM on Tomial's Blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>zh-cn</language><copyright>© Tomial</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2019 17:21:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tomial.github.io/tags/acm/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>ICPC Asia Urumqi 2017 B.The Difference</title><link>https://tomial.github.io/posts/icpc-asia-urumqi-2017-b-the-difference/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2019 17:21:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tomial.github.io/posts/icpc-asia-urumqi-2017-b-the-difference/</guid><description>&lt;p>Alice was always good at math. Her only weak points were multiplication and subtraction. To help her with that, Bob presented her with the following problem.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>He gave her four positive integers. Alice can change their order optionally. Her task is to find an order, denoted by &lt;code>A1,A2,A3&lt;/code> and &lt;code>A4&lt;/code>, with the maximum value of &lt;code>A1×A2 − A3×A4&lt;/code>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="input">Input&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The input contains several test cases and the first line provides an integer &lt;code>t(1 ≤ t ≤ 100)&lt;/code>indicating the number of cases.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>ICPC Asia Urumqi 2017 G.The Mountain</title><link>https://tomial.github.io/posts/icpc-asia-urumqi-2017-g-the-mountain/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2019 16:58:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tomial.github.io/posts/icpc-asia-urumqi-2017-g-the-mountain/</guid><description>&lt;p>All as we know, a mountain is a large landform that stretches above the surrounding land in a limited area. If we as the tourists take a picture of a distant mountain and print it out, the image on the surface of paper will be in the shape of a particular polygon.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>From mathematics angle we can describe the range of the mountain in the picture as a list of distinct points, denoted by&lt;code> (x1,y1)&lt;/code> to &lt;code>(xn,yn)&lt;/code>. The first point is at the original point of the coordinate system and the last point is lying on the &lt;code>x-axis&lt;/code>. All points else have positive &lt;code>y&lt;/code> coordinates and incremental &lt;code>x &lt;/code>coordinates. Specifically, all &lt;code>x&lt;/code> coordinates satisfy &lt;code>0=x1&amp;lt;x2&amp;lt;x3&amp;lt;...&amp;lt;xn&lt;/code>. All &lt;code>y&lt;/code> coordinates are positive except the first and the last points whose &lt;code>y&lt;/code> coordinates are zeroes.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>